India, my country.
Population 1.35 billion.
Half of them... Female.
Ask any girl and she'll
confess the dreams she nurtures,
mostly remaining unfulfilled.
Darling son will go to college,
while daughter will
stoke the kitchen fire!
She turns 18 and she'll be married off!
End of story.
But that's not what happened to me.
Instead of pots & pans...
I held a sword.
I'm Saina Nehwal, daughter of India.
Here I stand, sword in hand,
for another test,
another battle to be won.
Who challenges me never mattered.
My motto, crystal clear...
Demolish the opponent.
Saina serving at match point.
Now for her individual
Commonwealth Games gold medal.
Can you guess...
the travel speed of a powerful smash
hurtling towards the opponent?
If Shoaib Akhtar's cricket
ball travels at 161 kmph,
Malaysia's Tan Boon Hoe's shuttle
zips at 493 kmph and
destroys the opponent.
This one of mine was 357 kmph.
And she's done it!
Saina wins the women's
singles finals here at the 2018
Commonwealth Games.
An astounding performance
from Saina Nehwal.
A very special day
for all badminton fans.
It can be said that people
were not confident of Saina's win.
She really was the underdog today.
That's why this can be regarded
as a very important comeback for Saina.
And there on the court...
the Indian flag fluttering high.
Saina wins not one but two
gold medals in this tournament.
It's as if playing for her country...
lifts her game a couple
of notches to what's perfection.
The legend delivers yet again.
Saina Nehwal wins
2 gold medals for India.
Her motto is "Demolish the
opponent" and she went for the kill.
That's Saina Nehwal.
Saina, Saina!
Saina, Saina! Saina, Saina!
Congratulations Saina Nehwal.
Stupendous achievement.
For all of us as Indians to see
that national flag going high...
and to see that 'Jana Gana Mana'
getting sung on foreign soil.
We open the floor for Q/A now for all
of you to have an interaction with her.
Hi Saina, congratulations!
You were amazing!
What's the feeling like?
Umm...
How am I feeling?
Relief!
A million questions
from a thousand people.
How to answer?
What to answer?
Ya, I'm feeling very happy.
She gave me a tough fight
and it's a proud moment for India.
Hello Saina, after your success...
What was the turning point for you?
How do you manage to keep
your adrenaline rush in check?
Some of us were with you in Rio...
What do you prefer?
Win or Loss?
Of course, a win! Who wouldn't?
If I'd lost today, the verdict would be...
...the sun has set.
It's over for Saina.
Losses and wins keep happening.
Today she lost.
It's all part of the game.
We don't see this spirit in everyone.
From where do you muster this
courage, this strength?
My mother.
She's bullheaded...
...and I'm her child...
It's the DNA...What can I do?
Do you understand 'womb'?
Mother's womb.
The earliest lessons began from there.
Felt like I was being
tossed around in stormy waters.
What are you up to?
Stop being so stubborn.
Is it important to win?
Of course! I'm a Jat woman.
Won't quit until I win!
Somehow this ship
managed to find harbour.
Congratulations, it's a baby girl!
And from her full-throated wails,
seems very powerful.
Saina!
Ma! Ma,
look Saina is irritating me.
Statue! Statue!
Enough of this!
Doctor Saab,
why are you frozen like a statue?
You continue unpacking.
Statue's for the kids.
They're getting on my nerves!
Did you get details about
the badminton academy like I'd asked you to?
Oh god! Okay, okay.
Statue's off for you.
But not for you girls! Stay frozen.
Tell me!
What's with this stretching?
Tell me quickly.
It's 25 kms away.
Lal Bahadur Shastri Stadium.
They all teach there.
Nani Sir, Meru Sir, Aarif Sir.
So...
should I pickle this information?
The point is when are you
going to take this little one there?
Can't you see, she's turning
the whole house on its head?
...Have a backache.
Doctor Saab, you let it be.
You get ready, I'll take you there.
You just give me the bus fare.
C'mon get going, hurry up.
An hour already of this Hyderabad tour!
When will we reach Lal
Bahadur Shastri Stadium?
The holy pilgrimage of badminton.
Lal Bahadur Shastri Stadium.
LBS.
Big coaches!
Champion players!
An opportunity waiting to be grabbed!
Had to make a mark!
-What is your name?
-Anshika.
-Anshika. Yours?
-Tanishka.
-Sir...
-Joining date?
16th April.
Ma'am please don't disturb.
-Sorry sir. Please continue.
-Father's name?
Mohit.
Yes, please speak.
Sir, I want to enroll my daughter.
Admissions are full, madam!
Tanshika, Anshika, go to court 1.
Sir, please give her a chance...
Saina look!
Pick up the racket!
Show them your game.
Only then will they take notice of you.
Best of luck and play full power!
Out! Player change.
Serve.
Hit it! Hit it!
Yes, smashing!
Wonderful. Very nice!
Stop!
Whose racket is this?
Where are your badminton shoes?
Out!
Hey, stop.
Stop it.
Sir,...
she can't follow your language.
We're from Haryana.
-Are you her mother?
-Yes!
Mrs. Usha Rani Harvir Singhji Nehwal
and she's my younger one - Saina.
Saina.
Show me your grip.
Hey!
You're holding a racket or a sword?
Who's taught you this?
Sir, it's... it's me.
So do you also play?
Oh yes! I used to play
district level in Haryana.
We're from Hisar, not Panipat.
We just shifted to
Rajendra Nagar last week.
My husband is a PhD.
You bring her from tomorrow
for regular coaching.
For sword fighting!
Okay child, go and play now.
Kashyap!
Play with our warrior princess-
Rani Rudrama Devi.
She's selected!
-She's selected!
-What?
She's selected!
She demolished everybody!
No proper shoes,
just picked a racket and pushed her in.
She shocked girls head-taller than her.
The coach came to you after that...
and he said something
you didn't understand...
I told him that we aren't from here.
We are from Haryana.
And then we cracked it!
From tomorrow it's
regular coaching for her.
You mean tomorrow?
Yes Sir! Every morning
she has to reach at 5.
Fill up the scooter.
You'd said it's 25 kms away.
She's a champion.
You'll be World No. 1.
If not, you'll make her one.
Right Usha Rani?
I've peeled potatoes.
Should I toss them?
No! Today we'll have
parathas with white butter.
A place where breath doesn't race
Sleeping in even pace
where trees cast long
shadows that reach river banks
where the moon still
shines in still lakes
No conditions set on mirth
No fear of living on earth
Let me take you there,
Let me take you there
...To beat a new path
That first day of
coaching at LBS Academy...
Magical environment...
and Meru sir...
Buddy...
Blunt but with a heart of gold.
Why would anyone want
to do anything else!
Children, come, come.
Settle down.
Quick, quick.
Shhhh...
In India, people
play in their backyards
singing retro songs and call it
playing badminton.
Well that's not badminton.
Badminton is an indoor game.
An expensive game.
A shuttle drum costs 3000 bucks!
And to give wind to
this shuttle you need 5 S's...
Stamina.
Speed.
Strength.
Skill and...
Spirit!
Hold on to them.
Understood?
-Yes!
-Good.
Come on, get back to your courts.
Quick, quick.
Stamina lies in your roots.
And speed is in your DNA.
For strength....
I'll feed you parathas
with white butter,
almonds and fruit juice.
Skills, your sir will impart.
And spirit... I'll blow that into you!
Get ready, quick!
Come on, good going.
Keep it fast!
Training was in full force.
Wrist movement.
Shadows.
Reflexes.
And speed.
Lift!
Toss!
Keep!
Tap!
Smash!
Three!
No excuses! Drink it up!
My badminton foundation
was laid at LBS.
Also, I found my band-of-boys...
Nutty Damodar, endearing Rohan...
and most special...
Kashyap.
Sir, enter Saina for
the district competition.
What're you saying Mrs. Nehwal!
She's just...
Sir, competition is a great teacher.
But Mrs. Nehwal,
she's just learnt to hold a racket!
Sir, you give the bird the
sky and it'll surely take flight.
First game won by Saina Nehwal.
Second game.
Love all.
Play.
Point goes to Saina Nehwal.
Out!
Under-10 singles,
won by Saina Nehwal.
Very good.
Sit, sit.
I'll get milk for you.
Make sure all the children get milk!
Quick! Quick!
Match point for Saina
Nehwal & Riya Singh.
Under-10 doubles won
by Saina Nehwal & Riya Singh.
Under-13 singles won by Saina Nehwal.
This is the magic of milk.
Under-13 doubles won by
Saina Nehwal and Mithila Shah.
Hey, Meru.
Where did you find her?
I've been observing her since morning.
She sits stoic.
Mother brings her two glasses of milk.
She gulps them down.
Gets up, plays and wins!
Back again, sits,...
...gulps, up, plays and wins.
In 4 hours she's won 4 state titles!
Who is she?
Rana Sir.
Saina Nehwal.
An 8-year old child from Hisar rewrites
history in Vishakapatnam's State tournament.
She has earned a state record by
winning 4 state titles in a single day.
To dream of becoming No.1
is not without hazards.
Match won by Aditi Mutatkar.
11-7, 11-9.
Because if I deliver No. 2 instead of 1...
Mummy.
I had stood 2nd in the
National ranking tournament...
and this was the reward I got.
Repeatedly I've warned
her but she doesn't listen!
Gets dumbfounded.
Gave away 3 precious
points just like that.
Couldn't you see the shuttle
was headed out of line?
And what's that overhead
smash instead of a backhand shot?
Let her be.
Winning and losing are part of sports.
Someone has to lose.
Today it's you,
tomorrow it's me.
Don't butt in!
No need to fill her head up with ideas.
Lend her a shoulder and
you'll cripple her for life.
Don't glare at me!
Go to your room.
Sit with your books and study.
Didn't hear what I said?
And no dinner for you today!
Let it sink in first...
Take this.
Toss it.
Winning is prime for your mother.
Let me tell you an incident.
Back in Hisar,
I used to play mixed-doubles
with your mother as partner.
Then she lost the finals...
because of me.
Guess what she did?
She changed partners.
She dumped me!
Partnered with a
Mr. Ramesh Chand in order to win.
Frankly I feared...
she might run away
with Mr. Ramesh Chand!
Did Ma win?
Yes.
Now eat.
Tasty vegetable...
and roti.
Papa is very, very special.
Very good, my tigress!
Like Balraj Sahni of Do Bigha Zamin...
standing behind, stoic.
Earlier I used to imagine
Ma to be everything.
The tough, spirited, decision maker!
Learnt about Papa's quiet
contribution much later.
Papa shuttle!
Yes.
Here it is.
Excuse me.
Can you please lend me 2 shuttles?
I'll return them tomorrow.
I don't have, sorry.
Can I borrow 2 shuttles?
I'll give them back tomorrow,
definitely.
Sorry...
A drum of 10 shuttles costs 3000 Rupees.
How long will you keep
begging for them 2 at a time?
Forget badminton.
Not for everyone.
Give her education.
Make her able.
Got it?
Come in!
Sir!
What happened Doc?
Why are you panting?
Sir, I wanted a PF Loan, urgently.
Why?
Sir, I wanted a shuttle...
I mean, made a
lunge to grab the shuttle...
slipped and fractured the small toe...
also a ligament tear.
Whose?
My dau...
I mean, my wife.
Oh, I see.
Must do it urgently. Hand it to me.
Please sir.
Take the day off.
Thank you sir.
I'll take care of my wife, sir.
Papa shuttle.
Papa kept handing me
shuttles and I kept smashing.
I made it to the papers.
Papa made minuscule
reports look like headlines.
Saina Nehwal bags
a triple in the state.
Under-10 singles,
Under-13 singles & doubles.
Saina Nehwal from Andhra Pradesh emerges
victorious at the Sub-Junior Nationals.
She has left her mark
with her exceptional talents.
Each tournament,
each win, each medal, each award...
a result of mother's glowing spirit!
Ma & Papa...
like fire & water.
This harmonious balance brought a
little baby girl from Haryana
into the arena of the
National Singles Finals.
And another one for Saina Nehwal as
she storms into the National Finals.
Today we are at Chennai's Chidambaram Gardens
for the Junior National Championship.
Saina Nehwal, the emerging player
from Andhra Pradesh will face the...
3-time National Champion
Shehnaz Rizvi from Uttar Pradesh.
And Saina makes sure Shehnaz
fails to score any point.
Saina is just one point
away from winning this game.
11-love.
Game won by Saina Nehwal.
Wonderful performance!
They call her the wrestler from Haryana.
She showed them.
11-love.
Do you realize?
It's the National finals!
Not at all.
Looks like Shehnaz's been called
for Saina's practice.
Change sides.
Not so soon buddy!
Second game still remains.
She could lose.
Always negative.
Buzz off!
Wait and watch.
Out! Service change.
Love-all.
No problem.
She is still leading.
C'mon!
1-love.
2-love.
3-love.
4-love.
Look, she is going to lose.
Shut up!
In the spirit of winning,
no room for failure
C'mon Saina!
One life is all there is,
no second thought
Great one!
Service change.
Love-4.
Just focus.
-Why be a bird,
-1-4.
-When the sky is what I want to be
-She did a cross drop!
Why remain a mere page,
-When an epic is what I want to be
-That's it!
-3-4.
-Why be a bird,
-When the sky is what I want to be
-4 All
-5-4.
-Come on Shehnaz!
Why remain a mere page,
When an epic is what I want to be
8-4.
She won! She won the Nationals!
Game and match point
won by Saina Nehwal.
11-love.
11-4.
Go Saina!
Saina, Saina! Saina, Saina!
Haryana's buffalo, fatso...
can't recall what
all they used to call me.
But thanks to the
spirit which Ma fueled,
I shined at the Nationals.
Hold on! Hold on!
You're back!
Look, what's come today.
Finally, it's arrived!
You're going to play for India!
I knew it for over a week.
You hid this from me?
Your mother?
Gotten wiser, haven't you?
Let me hold it.
Hmm...
Nice, isn't it?
How does it look?
Suits you.
Make sure you win.
You've fulfilled my dream.
She's a champion.
"And if she doesn't,
you'll make her one"
Isn't that what you'd said?
Finally my champion
is heading overseas...
to play the Czech Open in Prague.
She'll represent India!
My daughter will play for India.
I should go and get your things.
We're leaving in 2 days.
What kind of things?
Don't increase the baggage weight, Ma.
Cashews, almonds, pistachios...
you don't worry about the weight.
Together we're allowed 46 kgs.
I've nothing to carry.
So it'll be fine.
Should I come with you?
No, you recover.
You've an evening session at 6.
I'll be back by then.
Should I get you a film DVD?
Yes.
Any Shahrukh Khan film will do.
-Saina!
-Yes?
Somebody fetch water.
Mummy! Mummy!!
One minute.
Mummy!
No, Papa is not at home.
He's not here.
Mummy!
-Where has the ambulance reached?
-On its way.
She's bleeding profusely!
Mummy!
Patient status?
Going into tachycardia doctor.
High chance of internal bleeding.
Oxygen level?
Dropping to 90%.
2 litres of oxygen on flow.
Six and a half hours in surgery...
and yet no idea...
if she'll survive or not.
Snatching back a hundred times
more than what you've given us...
... what is to happen Ma?
What happened?
Where are you going?
I'm heading for practice.
Pract...
but these are moments for prayer.
That's what I am heading to do.
A place where breath doesn't race
Sleeping in even pace
where trees cast long
shadows that reach river banks
-where the moon still shines in still lakes
-Serve!
No conditions set on mirth
No fear of living on earth
Let me take you there,
Let me take you there
...To beat a new path
Today, I would've smashed even
a solid cricket ball at 440 kmph!!!
Each smash, a plea.
Like clanging huge temple bells...
calling out to the
Almighty to save Ma's life.
But no answer.
Fearlessly step out of home,
Your heart shall lead you there...
It's the finals of the Junior Women
Singles here at Prague. The Czech Open.
And making her way at courtside,
Saina Nehwal of India facing
Yana Vorotnykova of Ukraine.
Where eyes have never known tears,
Finding a hundred excuses to smile...
Let me take you there,
They both have been in tremendous
form all along in this tournament.
-Yana getting us underway.
A brilliant smash.
Saina under pressure now.
- Yet again she catches
Saina wrong footed.
Reeling off winner after
winner from her racket.
And Saina making a comeback.
Brilliant play at the net.
Superb placement.
And now for a change of pace,
a lovely smash.
And brilliant placing again!
Down the line smash and she's won it!
Saina Nehwal from India.
The winner of the final
here in Prague at the Czech Open.
Playing on a big stage
for the first time.
This young girl hasn't
let her country down.
She has caused a major upset here.
The entire nation must be
celebrating this extraordinary win.
Yes?
Hey champion!
Be careful! She might get hurt.
Mummy, you had me scared!
Show me...
Just see!
The rightful owner of this medal...
Usha Rani Harvir Singh Nehwal aka Mummy!
What?
Yes, it's for you.
Hand it over.
Kashyap's face was a sight.
Mummy snatched the entire bouquet.
He somehow
managed to save one for me.
What's wrong with you today?
She took...
He is special.
Like badminton,
in life, timing is very important.
You miss the bus, you lost your chance.
Rajan is opening an academy in this city
so that talented players
get a chance to prove themselves.
The middle class in their struggle
for security burn out.
Dreams & passions remain unfulfilled.
I've seen how tired soles wear out
hustling for a single shuttle.
He'll teach... for free.
No money but he'll
demand herculean effort.
Not easy.
Powered like a tiger and
disciplined like an Army General.
If you can withstand that,
you get to play.
He's called us at 5, today.
I've brought you up to here
but if you want to be world champs,
I strongly recommend you
guys joining Rajan Academy.
LBS Stadium...
Like mother's home...
Not easy to leave...
The home that absorbed
all my idiosyncrasies...
I was stepping out of it's
threshold for the first time,
to count mother's dreams.
Rajan Sir!
Good morning champions!
Good morning sir!
I'm Rajan.
Welcome to my Academy.
Why've you guys come to me?
Anyone?
Actually I don't really know why.
But I clearly know why
I've built this academy.
If you want an admission
in college through the sports quota,
I have no place for you.
You want to show off
your medals and get a job,
I have no place for you.
You want to use it as
a passport to travel the world...
Get Out!
Right now!
Don't waste my time.
I haven't built this
academy to mint money.
I have built this academy
to create champions.
When I was on a winning spree,
I could've easily...
modelled for soft drinks, the ads
hanging from corner stores.
Comfortable life.
Pots of money.
But that would make me a
model and not a champion.
No!
Didn't want that.
As for you,...
I don't want a champion...
who thinks of winning.
I want a champion who...
thinks of winning...
and... nothing... else!
So tell me...
who thinks he'll become World No.1
badminton player?
Very good.
At least you think that way.
This hunger is necessary.
But as you know,
the Taj Mahal was not built in a day.
It requires a system.
And I have that system.
If you follow that system,
you'll win all the matches.
That's my promise.
But if you break any
rule of the academy...
then you're out!
One mistake and you are out!
Got that?
Yes sir.
-Got that?
-Yes Sir!
So you're waiting for coffee?
Let's start!
Okay start!
Stop it!
Saina!
Follow me.
Saina, what's your diet regime?
Sir? There's nothing like a diet regime.
What do you eat?
Let's start with breakfast.
Sir, for breakfast...
aloo parathas and a glass of milk.
How many?
4-5 parathas and Ma's instructions...
1.25 liters of milk daily.
Lunch?
Lunch... dal with rice, rotis and curd...
Got it, got it.
Saina...
your diet and your game...
are interlinked.
Badminton doesn't mean only power.
It's not wrestling!
It's very...
...delicate.
How to put it...
delicate (in Urdu).
Your smashes are good but...
smashes is not the game.
With strength,
you need to be agile... like a cat.
You know.
You've to be light on your feet.
Right now you're landing very heavy.
Reduce 10 kgs.
That too quickly.
So basically no parathas,
no milk, no curd, no ice cream.
I want results...
fast!
Got it?
This is your diet chart.
Follow it like the bible.
Sir, what do you mean by no milk?
I have to drink milk.
Go!
7 almonds, 5 walnuts,
boiled vegetables and 12 egg whites.
Every day 12 egg whites!
Then what do we do with the yolks?
Just one bite and lunch over.
Should I make one more roti?
Ridiculous.
No food allowed. No parents allowed.
Expecting a Haryana
girl to lose 10 kg weight.
No parathas, no ice cream.
Oh this badminton!
Burn up, Douse
Rise, Burn
Live, Die
Struggle, Survive
No requests, polite
Snatch that chance
Slip, Rise
Gain stride
lamber up to sky,
Step at a time
Caveat for the voyage
Never look back
In the spirit of winning,
no room for failure
One life is all there is,
no second thought
Why be a bird,
When the sky is what I want to be
Why remain a mere page,
When an epic is what I want to be
10.2 kilos. 48 days.
Agile. Deceptive. Anticipating.
Good.
Enough!
Do you even realize what you're doing?
You're playing brilliantly.
You've arrived.
Rohan, did you see?
Yes.
You should go and talk to Sir.
At best he'll say no, right?
Go meet him.
Saina...
remember... World No. 1?
You go.
Allot Nisha court number 1...
and tell her to practice for 2 hours.
Yes?
Sir, may I?
Come in.
Allot Ragini Pandey court number 2.
Ensure the shifting.
Give her 30 minutes.
Yes, tell me.
Sir... I needed to talk to you.
You must have observed I
defeat all the girls in the academy.
That's no big deal.
I want to do something big, Sir...
... send me for the Philippines Open.
I want to play.
But there's no Junior category there.
I'm aware, Sir. It's a World Series.
I want to play in the Women's category.
You want to play in the Seniors'?
Yes Sir.
You want to play with
the big girls of the world?
Do you know who's playing there?
Xu Huaiwen, Julia Wong.
They are the top players of the world.
So what Sir! I'll demolish them!
Sir, I'll break the Great Wall of China!
You want to break China's wall?
Okay. Write her name down.
But I won't be coming, though.
I'm busy with the other girls.
-If you'll not come, who will?
-Bimbisaar Babu.
Bimbisaar Babu?
Please don't do this Sir.
I don't have time.
You want to break The
Great Wall of China, right?
-Yes sir.
-So, why're you standing here?
Go practice.
-Give me.
-Yes sir.
Thank you sir.
Raman...
and Damodar.
Write his name.
Court four.
Sir, seriously... put her name?
It's a new tournament.
She'll watch the top players
of the world and pick up a thing or two.
Anyway, where've China & Malaysia
ever let India reach the quarters.
Big thing if she even
reaches the second round.
Can't understand players these days.
-Should I write her name down?
-Yes.
-Hey, seen Kashyap and gang?
-No.
Saina, World No. 1.
With this one gesture he stole my heart.
With so much faith invested
what else do you need to do?
Just go and demolish!
It began explosively.
Defeated Yin in the first
round and broke The Wall of China.
Finished Malaysia's
Lai in the second round.
And then Ai Goto of Japan.
Demolished every opponent.
For the first time an Indian
girl has stepped into the...
finals of an International World
Badminton Series.
That's Saina Nehwal!
-Usha Rani! Usha Rani!
-Mummy!
-What happened?
-Come fast.
Saina's in the news.
She is going to play in the finals
of the World Women's Philippines Open.
-Her photo!
-Hush!
She'll be facing Malaysia's
Julia Wong Pei Xian.
Will Saina create history?
Every Indian is pinning hopes on her.
I'm Yogita Awasthi for AGCPL News,
signing off!
I'm so happy she reached the finals!
Just a few seconds to go for the
commencement of the Women's Singles
Final here in Manila
at the Philippines Open.
We've got the tournament favourite
Julia Wong up against this...
young sensation Saina Nehwal.
The contest seen for the
first time on such a big stage.
On my right, Julia Wong from Malaysia.
On my left, Saina Nehwal from India.
There she is!
Julia to serve.
Love all. Play.
Julia Wong to serve in
this Women's Singles final.
Missing that, Julia Wong!
Very good.
And that should give Saina some confidence
in these early opening stages.
Brilliant smash by Saina down the line.
-Looking very powerful indeed.
-Did you see?
I knew it.
Once again the round-the-head smash
paying enormous dividends for Saina.
Saina's power play coming to the fore!
Again! And Again!
Back to back points here
with an explosive gameplay.
She's got Julia on tenterhooks at
this final.
-19-14.
-C'mon! Last 2 points left.
Smashes it on the line!
Twenty game point fifteen.
I don't think Julia was expecting such
explosive gameplay from young Saina here.
Terrific power!
Wooaah! And with that
Saina wraps up this first game.
21-15.
First game won by Saina Nehwal.
Get the sweets ready.
Sir, she won the first game. 21-15.
She'll win the second set also.
Saina's been terrific this tournament
and she continues her
good form in today's game.
Who could've thought that an 86th
ranked player like Saina Nehwal...
would send shivers down
the spine of Julia Wong.
Players back on court.
Julia Wong under pressure.
Absolutely trounced in that first game.
She walks back into
court after pep talk.
She needs to win this second game.
I anticipate very solid &
very strong play from both players.
Second game.
Love all. Play.
Saina getting us underway here.
Oh! An unforced error there from Saina.
One-love.
She's not going to be happy about that.
She knows how valuable
these early points are.
Good play by Julia!
And, oh!
Excellent judgement there by Julia.
Saina relying too much on her power play.
Julia Wong playing a
purely tactical game here.
The talk of the coach clearly working.
There again!
Julia getting the better of Saina.
Interval.
Saina Nehwal with her
back up against the wall.
Julia Wong with a huge lead at 11-2...
as we head into the mid-game interval.
Julia had suddenly begun dominating me.
It's as if she'd read my natural game.
I was just smashing away.
Need to change gear.
Against the world's most
promising badminton player,
playing instinctively is not enough.
I need strategy.
11-2. Play.
Julia Wong to resume play.
Perfect play from Saina.
Agility.
Quickness.
Light on the feet like a cat.
Beautifully placed!
3-11! 4-11! 5-11! 6-11!
Deception.
Lead elsewhere, then shift target!
Show one, do another!
Julia Wong with her back to the ropes.
It's unbelievable what's happening here.
Anticipation.
Wait for the shuttle.
And then, smash!
And she's done it!
She clinched the Philippines Open.
She has just become the
first Indian woman to win a
four-star International Badminton
event and in such a grand fashion.
I mean the fight back in
the second game was unbelievable.
This has been a privilege...
to witness the arrival of this
young star on the badminton horizon.
Wonderfully whittled by badminton
champion coach Sarvadhamaan Rajan.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
remember the name, Saina Nehwal.
She is here to stay.
-Hello.
-Hey!
How does it feel?
We were watching
you live at the academy.
What fun!
What're you doing?
Sitting in my hotel room and
eating a scoop of vanilla ice-cream...
all by myself.
All by yourself!
So, should I have
it with Bimbisaar Babu?
But must admit,
it tastes as sweet, even alone.
What?
Ice-cream... or Victory?
Saina, Saina!
Saina, Saina! Saina, Saina!
All of you, please wait outside.
Please, please.
I must admit,
you beat my expectations.
More power to you.
Thank you Sir.
A lot of media outside.
Not good to keep them waiting.
Okay Sir.
Ma'am, Ma'am.
He's dreamt this dream with us
and he is very happy with the win.
Ma'am, Ma'am.
The soaring heights of achievement
are intoxicating.
Lost in the high, you never realize
that there could be turbulence in the flight ahead.
Surprise!
Happy birthday, happy birthday!
Wake up, sleeping beauty.
She is without her badminton racket.
It's 12 o'clock.
She's still thinking
it's her 3 AM practice alarm.
Just stop it.
Happy birthday!
Enough.
Let him sing.
Aunty, he'll sing the whole song.
Happy birthday Saina.
The feel of your breath,
I hold close to me
Your happiness and your pain,
I claim as mine
The heart wishes that you smile,
Nothing to fear
I'm near, I'm near
Never was, nor will be
As dear
I'm near, I'm near
Never was, nor will be
As dear
It's the same rose I gave you.
Papa had given this
to Mummy before marriage.
Oh!
Of course it's the same rose, you fool!
Look around you,
No one, but us
Both pining...
New longings of first timers,
Never felt before
Wherever I turn, I carry with me,
Cannot escape your scent
Haven't had to ask for more,
From the day I met you
Wasting myself in your arms,
Till day turns to night
I'm near, I'm near
Never was, nor will be
As dear
Wow!
I'm near, I'm near
Never was, nor will be
As dear
I'm near, I'm near
Never was, nor will be
As dear
-Relax Saina. It's not a race.
-Then stay behind.
-Saina.
-Yes, Sir?
Yes, Sir.
-Kashyap.
-Sir.
Out.
Sir?
Leave.
What happened, Sir?
You know, the shelf life
of a player is very short.
Youth is very deceptive.
It distracts first...
then destructs.
To spend your youth on a relationship
is like committing suicide...
Hara-kiri!
I know, Sir.
I'm giving my 100 percent.
Is it?
Yes sir...
You always find the
same partner to practice with?
I have eyes.
I can see what is happening.
What is happening Sir?
I'll tell you!
Right now an army of a hundred
people are running for you.
Trainers, coaches, team.
And leading them from the front is
the country's best & top most family -
dedicated, devoted, focused -
the Nehwal family!
They are carrying you on
their shoulders and running...
and you want to jump
off and get married.
-No sir.
-Is it?
Or you want to be World No. 1.
Yes Sir.
I don't get into anybody's
personal matters or private life.
I don't like it and that's not my style.
I focus only on focus.
Eye on the eye because
that's my job as a coach.
I want to make you World No. 1!
Do you want that?
-Yes Sir.
-Do you want that really?
Yes Sir.
I'll say this one last time.
After that no discussion.
Got it?
What you 'Do' to win
a game is not important.
What is important is what
you 'Sacrifice' to win the game.
Just remember that.
What did Sir say, Saina?
Do I look stupid to you?
No.
Since I was 8,
when other girls played with dolls...
and attended birthdays and fairs...
I've gotten up at 3
in the morning for training.
All my life I've played only
badminton and done nothing else.
Don't I realize the sacrifices Mummy,
Papa and Abu have made for me?
Does someone else have
to point that out to me?
Does Sir need to point that out to me?
Sacrifices!
I don't want to meet you.
What're you saying Saina?
Why don't they ask Sachin
why he married at 22?
Because he is a male player.
I'm a girl!
My feelings don't matter.
I don't want to meet you.
Please don't say this, Saina.
-I don't want to meet you!
-Saina, please listen to me...
Sir told me... leave. I did.
Not a single question.
Did exactly what he advised.
It brought result.
A new name in the international arena.
Saina Nehwal from India qualifies
for the Olympics' Quarter Finals!
Saina wins the Chinese Taipei Open!
Saina wins World Junior Championships!
The first Indian to do so.
Not easy to brush away your past.
Had to do it because
Badminton stood as my future.
Just like Dronacharya's Arjun,
I could now clearly see the bird's eye.
Then began my winning streak...
a flood of World Titles.
My punches landing right!
India makes history by winning it's
first gold medal in Badminton...
in the history of Commonwealth Games.
Crowd here in Siri
Fort hysterical with joy!
My Guru's face lit
like a 1000 watt bulb.
-Now that's her Commonwealth gold.
-And the cherry on the cake,
India's first Olympic
medal in Badminton.
That changed everything for me.
Welcome Saina! Please do the honours.
Okay, costume clear.
Out, out. Makeup out.
Saina ready?
-Yes.
-Okay...and...
Action!
Flamingo. An aid for a new life.
Presenting Oleev Active, the ultimate
cooking oil, for everyday cooking.
Samrat Atta.
A taste that brings all together.
Excuse me.
Yes ma'am.
What's going on?
My 2 hour commitment is over.
I've been waiting since
morning with this make-up on.
Can you let me know?
I'm missing my practice.
I have to go.
Please call my manager.
Sorry ma'am. We'll just start.
Why is the court empty?
Where's Saina?
She requested for 2 hours.
Again?
The court is reserved & it's empty while
players are queuing up waiting.
Superb.
Lovely!
Beautiful!
Superb!
Champs.
You can use this court.
Enough is enough.
If the court is reserved
& the player is not present, use it.
Even if it's Saina.
One more. One more. One more.
Sir, one more won't happen.
I've been smashing
full power since morning.
If I slip or injure myself,
what'll happen to my game?
Let's just do a few
more & then we'll wrap it.
I've been meaning to ask you.
Isn't Saina crossing limits?
She's become a youth icon of our nation.
After Sachin... it's Saina.
But so much advertising exposure?
How're you allowing this?
Olympic medalist, World No. 2.
I didn't have the heart to stop her.
One ad after the other...
This endorsement, that endorsement.
And then those managers!
God!
I didn't want to force my will.
Shouldn't be a case of sour grapes.
How can it be a case
of sour grapes with you?
Offers and opportunities made
a bee-line outside your house, then.
I mean, you could've been the poster
boy for the Satellite Revolution, Rajan.
Parvati...
success is a heady brew.
It's a high.
If you can't digest it,
it can lead to an upset.
Finished?
Almost done...
Nice!
Sorry Sir.
Sorry Sir...
Sir, I needed to talk to you.
Okay change, change. You go.
Change.
Saina, do you remember
your first day here?
Remember what I had said?
Want to be photographed
with soft drinks?
Want to hang in posters
at corner stores?
Get Out!
Right leg, I said right! Stretch!
Better.
When I had built this academy,
brick by brick,
I had thought it'll bear
fruit in the form of champions,
who shall serve the sport of Badminton.
To sell soaps and oils,
my coaching is not required.
Sir..
Saina, I've never feared for those...
who dream big which remain unfulfilled...
...the fear is for those who dream small...
and fulfill them.
Now if you'll excuse me...
these tiny-tiny children
are seeing big-big dreams...
... and they need me... or
should I say...
I need them.
From now on, you'll train with
Bimbisaar Babu.
Sir...
Okay, everyone come here!
I want to ask you, who is a champion?
-Me! Me!
-Only 4?
Me too! Me!
A teacher's blessings...
are like a warrior's shield.
Where did I lose my shield?
Why did I lose my shield?
Match won by Yui Hashimoto.
Match won by Sun Yui 21-16, 21-15.
21-17, 21-10.
Title goes to Wan Yihan.
Wonder what's happened
to Saina Nehwal's game.
Doesn't seem to be in good nick.
And Saina Nehwal slips!
Guess she has twisted her heel.
Looks like she's in unbearable pain.
The doctors have arrived on court.
They are checking Saina's injury.
Guess Saina needs a stretcher.
We have been told it's a serious injury.
Hey, are you feeling okay?
I'll give you a rundown on her feeling.
The doctor has prescribed
a 2 month rehab.
Has even forbidden from
putting her foot on the ground.
With game comes injury.
Papa, everything is fine.
Did Rajan Sir visit?
He's in Jakarta.
Tomorrow the whole troop is returning.
Ma'am. It's time for a sponge bath.
Step outside.
Let's go.
The bad news is that due to her injury,
Saina Nehwal has slipped from World No. 2
to World No. 9.
She's so bad that she can't
even step on to the court.
Meanwhile,
her juniors are scaling new heights.
The way the scales
are tipping for Saina,
the glorious sun of Saina's run seems
to be dipping into the horizon.
It's Yogita Awasthi for AGCPL News,
signing off!
Guys, coffee?
Saina, do you want a coffee?
So, how was Jakarta?
Wasn't good.
Forget it.
Chill.
Which is the next one?
Copenhagen.
I wish I could also come.
Why do you need to come, Saina.
You have everything. 2010. 2012.
Such fabulous years.
You have all the Super Series
Championships and an Olympic Bronze too.
Who has these many titles in India?
Just take a chill pill. Relax.
Write a fab autobiography.
You've got lots of time on your hands now.
Are you done? Should we leave?
What happened?
Wow.
One injury...
and these guys have
turned me into a flashback.
Somethings' going wrong, K.
These last 2 years haven't been good.
Something's missing.
The elephant walks
undaunted while dogs bark.
Your process is different, Saina.
Go meet Rajan Sir. Talk to him.
Resolve all of this.
You need to get back into action.
Keeping the knee straight.
Very good.
Take it down.
Up.
-Slowly down.
-Saina!
Bend it more.
Take it down. Very good.
Chew it.
One. Two.
Move your fingers down & up.
One more.
And now relax.
Get up!
You can do it.
All okay?
-Oh, surprise.
-Hello Sir.
Come on, sit.
Don't think you can begin practice.
Yes Sir. They're saying it'll take time.
Sir, you didn't come to the hospital.
Lot of work here.
So you've come to meet
your friends?
No Sir.
I've come to meet you.
Great.
So, should I stand
up or you'll sit down?
No Sir, why would you stand up.
I actually wanted to ask you something.
Please.
Sir, looks like you've forgotten me,
haven't forgiven me.
I did what you told me to,
but I fell out of your view.
My game was slipping
but you didn't step in.
Sir, I needed your time, Sir.
And I didn't give you my time, right?
I built this academy so
that one day I would witness
Saina Nehwal being crowned World No. 1.
-You know that, right?
-Yes Sir.
I accepted everything that
you did beyond the rule book.
You knew the academy rule...
...One mistake and you're out.
Did I do that?
-Sir, please I...
-I'm serious!
From 2004 I have been
giving you 6 hours every day...
that means if I put math to it...
25,920 hours of practice.
My time. My investment.
Yes sir.
Even after investing
such a lot of time...
if I failed to make you World No. 1...
then it means... I lack something.
I failed.
-No Sir. What are you saying...
-What do I say then?
That 'you' lack something.
'You' are not good enough.
'You' failed. Huh?
Sir...
why are you saying all this?
So you tell me,
if you were in my place,
what would you say?
Sir...
I would say...
that, maybe this academy
isn't right for you, Saina.
Wow.
So you've made your decision, already.
Sir, one should take
one's own decisions.
Thought about your future?
I wouldn't worry about
that if I were you.
Leaving the academy
or badminton as well?
Sir, can't quit badminton.
But yes, I'm leaving today what I can.
Best of luck.
Had gone to mend what had gone sour.
Instead, got trapped in
the war of words and on impulse...
destroyed the bridge irreparably.
Sir, are the rumours true that
Saina & Rajan are not on speaking terms?
Has Saina been told
to leave Rajan Academy?
Is this the end of the road for Saina?
What to do with them?
What should we tell them?
After leaving the academy
and the coach where will you go?
What will you do?
Papa, I don't have any answer...
Where will I go... To whom will I go...
Wherever you'll go and train,
you'll make them proud.
Don't give importance to the
media circus. Just focus on your game.
Don't allow self-doubt to creep in.
You are a tigress.
Saina Nehwal is your name!
Ma took control of the situation.
She suggested, we leave the city.
We shifted to Bengaluru.
Big problem.
Cinderella has lost her shoe.
What?
Don't know?
Want an answer?
Yes Sir.
Have you seen the 'Hall of Mirrors'?
Have you watched Mughal-e-Azam?
In that film there is 'Sheesh Mahal'.
Just like that, we have a
'Hall of Mirrors' in our academy.
Would you like to step in? Would you?
There was a little girl.
She had many six packs.
She was engineered for high end
attacks.
One day she had a fall,
it was beyond her call.
Her spectacle fell off her
nose and crumbled.
Lol. Now how to get the vision,
how to get insight?
As she'd never-
ever visited the mirror-lined hall.
Come.
Seems to have said something
I didn't get.
Saina. Saina. Saina. Saina. Saina...
Okay, settle down.
Settle down students.
The day they got to know
that Saina Nehwal is coming here...
they have called a strike
and waited for one
glimpse of their goddess.
Saina, when I saw you
play I decided to be like you.
Saina, you drink magic potion?
You play so well.
Saina, is your mother strict?
Is it true,
you drink 2 liters of milk every day?
Yes, it's true.
Excuse me.
I am Saina.
I walk like Saina, I talk like Saina,
I eat like Saina, I dress like Saina.
My fashion Saina, my style Saina.
My Instagram Saina,
my Twitter Saina, my Facebook Saina.
My racket Saina, my shoes Saina.
My everything Saina.
How are you little one?
Saina...
this is the hall of mirrors.
Your reflections.
This is what you mean to the sport -
to the empowerment of little
girls all over the country.
Whatever you do from here,
just remember...
what 'Saina Nehwal' means to the world.
You are the single most
important thing...
that has happened to young
women in this sport - in this country.
Remember, you are the tigress of India.
And it would be my
honor to be your coach...
and to be standing by your
side when you become World No. 1.
Start now, start immediately.
What a crackling day!
The children were a riot!
You should've been here.
Okay listen... we've landed here
without enough to sustain.
-Kashyap's coming...
-Yes.
So fill our things in the
big suitcase and send it with him.
Things are arranged here.
Number 2.
The path ahead was difficult.
I immediately began training.
-Plus, I had my pillar of strength...
-Number 4.
... my Kashyap.
Let's go, one more.
Come on.
-One more. One more.
-Come on, Saina.
The Taj Mahal wasn't built in a day.
Mine too, was left unfinished...
I had to repay the debt of 25,920 hours.
It was a second coming for me.
The start was slow yet steady.
Saina on a comeback trail.
Through to the Denmark
Super Series Quarter Finals.
I started my winning
trot with the China Open.
Saina wins the China
Open Super Series Finals.
Within 6 months my
world ranking improved.
I felt that I was getting
closer to the summit.
But there was another
tigress across the continent,
preparing for the same summit.
-Look!
-...Carla Martinez.
Look, how she screeches.
Scares the opponent!
Breaks the rhythm of the opponent!
With rhythm shattered,
confidence withers!
Without confidence
who can win against her?
She was in her best form then
and when it was time
for the Syed Modi Tournament
it was imperative that I defeat
her in order to emerge as World No. 1.
But the big question was...
... how to defeat her?
The stage is set here
in Lucknow for the..
Syed Modi International Grand Prix Gold
Women's Singles Final..
featuring Saina Nehwal of India
versus Carla Martinez of Spain.
It's a mouthwatering matchup between the
two best women's singles players
in the world on current form.
The badminton fans across the world
are looking forward to this match.
Exactly!
And leading the way into the arena,
here comes India's Saina Nehwal
welcomed by cheering and
applause by this mammoth crowd.
And here comes Saina's formidable
opponent, Carla Martinez,
the reigning Women's
Singles world champion.
Anil, both Saina and
Carla are in their best form.
Exactly! To predict a winner
between them is very difficult.
Head. Tails.
Heads.
You'll call?
It's heads.
Toss is in Carla's favour.
-That side.
-That side? Okay.
Any player would've chosen to serve.
But by choosing my side,
she'd declared war.
Knowingly she has chosen Saina's side,
to unsettle her.
On my right - Saina
Nehwal representing India...
India and on my left
- Martinez representing Spain.
Saina Nehwal to serve.
Love all, play.
Saina, Saina! Saina, Saina!
A good start from Martinez.
Always plays like this.
Points 1-love.
Anil, this is the specialty
of Martinez's gameplay.
Aggressive and dominating play.
Absolutely! Against Carla, an error
here or there and you're nowhere.
That's a very uncharacteristic
unforced error by Martinez.
Points 1 all.
Is that a sign of nerves?
Oh oh! She's trying
to break Saina's rhythm.
Not all games are played
on the court, are they?
On battleground, one distracted moment,
and the damage is done.
Each point, a game of life and death.
Saina, focus.
Just focus.
A fiery rally between the two players.
Must be a reason for the
beating heart to not bend it's will
That's the point...
to pull off what others couldn't
One life is all there is,
-Points 10-9.-no second thought
Both players pushing their
abilities to the maximum.
20-19.
Carla at game point.
Why be a bird,
When the sky is what I want to be
Why remain a mere page,
When an epic is what I want to be
Saina hitting it deep.
Martinez gets into position,
right under the shuttle there.
And she leaves!!
Excellent judgement
there from Carla Martinez.
She wins the first game 21-19.
Players on court please.
Stare at me today, red hot Sun
Tomorrow's my turn
-Brilliant smash.
-4-love.
I have double the fire
Strike when the iron is hot,
What's there to think about
13-7.
A great comeback from Saina Nehwal In
this second game.
Second game won by Saina Nehwal. 21-16.
-When the sky is what I want to be
-Very good!
And it's one game all.
Impossible to predict which
way the decisive third game will go.
The start is very
important in this game.
Players back on court please.
After two thrilling & engrossing games,
this match enters the
third and decisive game.
Saina Nehwal to serve.
Love all, play.
Excellent court coverage by Saina.
Creating that opportunity for
that brilliant round the head smash.
Points 1-love.
A good start from Saina Nehwal.
And that's a befitting
response by Carla Martinez.
Martinez getting off to a flyer
leading 5-1 now.
Anil, don't you think
her aggression...
is affecting Saina's game?
Absolutely!
Saina's got to do everything in
her power to filter it out.
A wonderful down the line smash.
A befitting response from Saina.
She gave it back.
Points 2-5.
Oh Martinez misses that one.
Lovely!
Saina clawing her
way back into this game.
Immense hard work for each point.
Points 10-9.
Heading to mid-game interval.
And Martinez takes the point.
Points 11-9.
Interval.
It's such a close game!
Anil, but I must admit,
Carla has a slight edge.
I agree. Carla brimming with confidence.
And look at the coaches.
The mid-game interval is
where their contribution comes in.
Enjoy!
Players back on court please.
Martinez getting us underway.
Thanks to this brilliant smash by
Martinez, she is leading with 12-9.
An astounding backhand smash.
Martinez leading 13-9.
It's 14-9.
C'mon Saina!
Saina, Saina! Saina, Saina!
And don't they love her.
The crowd participating there.
The Ho-Ha, Ho-Ha!
And amazingly she's raised her game.
Very good!
Saina going for the
kill with lethal smashes.
Both players are showcasing their
best form in this tough competition.
This match has been
on for more than an hour.
A badminton match like this demands
more stamina than a day's cricket match.
Both players look completely exhausted.
These tough women aren't done yet.
It's badminton of the highest order.
One thing's for sure.
Whichever way this match goes,
badminton is the true winner.
Points 23 all.
Saina!
Saina...
you're holding a racket or a sword?
Who thinks he'll become
World No.1 badminton player?
Like the human pyramid game...
... only one reaches the top...
... but helped by the shoulders
of team mates to reach the heights.
The pot of gold is in clear sight now,
one should lunge!
If you slip and fall, those
very shoulders will absorb your fall.
But if you hit jackpot...
... then you've created history!
Martinez serving at 23-all
in this humdinger of a contest.
And that's gone out,
giving Saina match point.
Match point 23.
Oh wait a minute!
Carla Martinez challenges
the shuttle call out!
Upon Martinez's challenge
the whole stadium goes silent.
And it's out by the
narrowest of margins.
Saina on match point. 24-23.
Points 24. Match point 23.
Oh that's taken the racket frame!
And Saina's totally
out of position for that.
She puts in a desperate dive.
And amazingly she reaches the shuttle
millimeters from the ground.
And she's done it!
Saina wins the Syed
Modi Grand Prix Gold!
What a fitting finale
to a sensational match!
Look at her!
On top of the world.
A superhuman effort
that will remain etched
in the memory of everyone
privileged to have seen it.
It was such a thrilling match.
Absolutely!
This victory of Saina over Carla Martinez
signaling a new era in Indian badminton.
In badminton's history, this match
will be written in golden words.
You must think becoming
World No.1 is enough.
But no...
that's not enough.
The hopes of over 1.25 billion
people attached to an athlete,
never allow you to rest.
Slip, Rise, Gain stride.
The cycle keeps repeating itself.
Again and again and again.
And at such times,
it's your own, that matter.
Your Mummy, your Papa,
your family, your friends ...
Actually I think I should go now.
Need to hand over these
medals to their true owners.
Thank you everybody.
I didn't know anything
about the Olympics and badminton.
Today if I see this 'Beti Bachao,
Beti Padhao' campaign,
I don't think it's needed.
The things the girls are doing today,
it's fantastic!
In the last Olympics also it was
only the girls who won medals.
I think everywhere the girls are
one step ahead in sports at the moment.
I'm really happy to be a girl.